Register of the William H. Rehnquist papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1971-2005
  - Lecture, University of Wisconsin Law School, Madison, Wisconsin, 1976 September 17 (Box-folder 204: 6)
    Typescript outline and correspondence
  - Speech, Retired Men's Club, Whitefish Bay, Wisconsin, 1976 September 20 (Box-folder 204: 7)
    Typescript, clipping, and correspondence
  - The First Amendment: Freedom, Philosophy, and the Law, William O. Douglas Lecture, Gonzaga University School of Law, Spokane, Washington, 1976 October 19 (Box-folder 204: 8)
  - Remarks, White House Fellows meeting, 1976 October 27 (Box-folder 204: 9)
  - Speech, Inter-Agency Seminar Group, Washington, D.C., 1976 November 16 (Box-folder 204: 10)
  - Speech, Public Policy Conference for Federal Executives, Brookings Institution, Virginia Beach, Virginia, 1976 November 19 (Box-folder 204: 11)
  - Sunshine in the Third Branch, speech, School of Law, Washburn University, Topeka, Kansas, 1977 January 27 (Box-folder 205: 1)
  - Reflections on Eight Years in Washington, Joseph Lincoln Lecture, College of Business Administration, Arizona State University, Tempe, Arizona, 1977 February 7 (Box-folder 205: 2)
  - A Jurist's View of Arbitration, speech, American Arbitration Association luncheon, Phoenix, Arizona, 1977 February 8 (Box-folder 205: 3)
  - Speech, Metropolitan St. Louis Lawyers' Wives Association, St. Louis, Missouri, 1977 March 10 (Box-folder 205: 4)
  - Speech, Landon School, Bethesda, Maryland, 1976 April 12 (Box-folder 205: 5)
    Holograph and correspondence
  - Moot court panel, Villanova University, Villanova, Pennsylvania, 1977 April 16 (Box-folder 205: 6)
  - Moot court panel, University of California, Los Angeles, California, 1977 May 6 (Box-folder 205: 7)
    Correspondence and photograph only
  - Speech, Stanford Law School alumni dinner, San Francisco, California, 1977 May 7 (Box-folder 205: 8)
  - Commencement address, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1977 May 15 (Box-folder 205: 9)
  - Speech, Constitutional Law Committee of the Federal Bar Association, Washington, D.C., 1977 May 16 (Box-folder 205: 10)
  - Doctor, Lawyer, Merchant, Chief, John M. Orem Memorial Lecture, Sibley Hospital, Washington, D.C., 1977 September 20 (Box-folder 205: 11)
  - Meeting, Cornell Law School Advisory Council, 1977 September 30 (Box-folder 205: 12)
  - Speech, Student Legal Forum, University of Virginia Law School, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1977 November 18 (Box-folder 205: 13)
  - The Nature and Exercise of Judicial Power, lecture, Honors Forum, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware, 1977 November 21 (Box-folder 205: 14)
  - Moot court panel, Yale Law School, New Haven, Connecticut, 1977 December 3 (Box-folder 205: 15)
  - The Adversary Society, Baron de Hirsch Meyer Lecture, University of Miami Law School, Miami, Florida, 1978 February 2 (Box-folder 206: 1)
  - Speech, Metropolitan St. Louis Lawyers' Wives Association, St. Louis, Missouri, 1978 April 4 (Box-folder 206: 2)
  - Moot court panel, Boston University, Boston, Massachusetts, 1978 April 11 (Box-folder 206: 3)
  - Moot court panel, New York University, New York City, 1978 May 2 (Box-folder 206: 4)
  - Meeting, Phi Delta Phi Legal Institute, Washington, D.C., 1978 May 5 (Box-folder 206: 5)
  - Remarks, Judicial Conference of the Ninth Circuit, Phoenix, Arizona, 1978 May 18 (Box-folder 206: 6)
  - Remarks, White House Fellows luncheon, 1978 May 23 (Box-folder 206: 7)
  - Panel discussion on appellate advocacy, American Bar Association, Washington, D.C., 1978 May 26 (Box-folder 206: 8)
    Transcript and correspondence
  - The Courts: Are They Really the 'Least Dangerous Branch' of the Government, Hoban Forum Lecture, University of Scranton, Scranton, Pennsylvania, 1978 September 19 (Box-folder 206: 9)
  - Speech, California District Attorneys Association, San Diego, California, 1978 October 24 (Box-folder 206: 10)
  - Moot court panel, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California, 1979 January 26 (Box-folder 206: 11)
    Correspondence and photographs only
  - Remarks, Capitol Hill Chapter, Federal Bar Association, Washington, D.C., 1979 April 2 (Box-folder 206: 12)
  - The Supreme Court of the United States: The Ohio Connection, lecture, University of Dayton School of Law, Dayton, Ohio, 1979 April 3 (Box-folder 206: 13)
  - Who Will Regulate the Regulators? speech, Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, New York, 1979 May 1 (Box-folder 207: 1)
  - Moot court panel, University of Toledo College of Law, Toledo, Ohio, 1979 May 5 (Box-folder 207: 2)
  - Commencement address, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1979 May 20 (Box-folder 207: 3)
  - Robert H. Jackson: A Perspective Twenty-Five Years Later, lecture, Albany Law School, Union University, Albany, New York, 1979 September 14 (Box-folder 207: 4)
  - Speech, St. Mary's University of San Antonio, San Antonio, Texas, 1979 October 20 (Box-folder 207: 5)
  - Act Well Your Part: Therein All Honor Lies, speech, Pepperdine University, Malibu, California, 1979 November 17 (Box-folder 207: 6)
  - Remarks, Republican Policy Committee luncheon, 1979 November 20 (Box-folder 207: 7)
  - Panel discussion, Close Up Foundation seminar, Washington, D.C., 1979 December 13 (Box-folder 207: 8)
  - Remarks, District of Columbia law clerks luncheon, Washington, D.C., 1980 January 21 (Box-folder 208: 1)
  - Remarks, McLean Lawyers Association meeting, McLean, Virginia, 1980 January 29 (Box-folder 208: 2)
  - Government by Cliché, lecture, University of Missouri School of Law, Columbia, Missouri, 1980 March 7 (Box-folder 208: 3)
    Typescript, proofs, correspondence, and clipping
  - Moot court panel, University of Alabama School of Law, University, Alabama, 1980 April 1 (Box-folder 208: 4)
  - Moot court panel, Georgetown University Law Center, Washington, D.C., 1980 April 9 (Box-folder 208: 5)
  - Remarks, White House Fellows and Judicial Fellows luncheon, Washington, D.C., 1980 May 7 (Box-folder 208: 6)
  - Remarks, United States Court of Claims law clerks luncheon, Washington, D.C., 1980 May 9 (Box-folder 208: 7)
  - A Bad Settlement Is Better than a Good Lawsuit, commencement address, University of Pittsburgh Law School, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1980 May 24 (Box-folder 208: 8)
  - Edward Douglass White Lecture, American Family Institute, Washington, D.C., 1980 June 5 (Box-folder 208: 9)
  - Panel, Federal Bar Association Younger Federal Lawyer Award, Washington, D.C., 1980 August 28 (Box-folder 208: 10)
  - 'All Discord, Harmony not Understood': The Performance of the Supreme Court of the United States, McCormick Lecture, University of Arizona College of Law, Tucson, Arizona, 1980 October 23 (Box-folder 208: 11)
  - Point, Counterpoint: The Evolution of American Political Philosophy, Cecil Sims Lecture, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee, 1980 November 18 (Box-folder 209: 1)
  - Moot court panel, J. Reuben Clark Law School, Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah, 1981 February 6 (Box-folder 209: 2)
  - Remarks, American College of Trial Lawyers meeting, Coronado, California, 1981 March 17 (Box-folder 209: 3)
  - Moot court panel, Stanford Law School, Stanford University, Stanford, California, 1981 April 10 (Box-folder 209: 4)
  - Speech, Judicial Conference of the Ninth Circuit, Moran, Wyoming, 1981 June 30 (Box-folder 209: 5)
  - Welcome to the Profession, commencement address, Delaware Law School, Widener University, Wilmington, Delaware, 1982 May 15 (Box-folder 209: 6)
  - Speech, Judicial Conference of the Ninth Circuit, Coronado, California, 1982 July 28 (Box-folder 209: 7)
  - Are the True Old Times Dead? Mac Swinford Lecture, University of Kentucky, Lexington, Kentucky, 1982 September 23 (Box-folder 210: 1)
    Holograph, typescript, and correspondence
  - Speech, State Bar of Arizona meeting, Phoenix, Arizona, 1983 February 11 (Box-folder 210: 2)
  - Lions under the Throne, Edward Douglass White Lecture, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, Louisiana, 1983 March 10 (Box-folder 210: 3)
    Typescript and printed copy
  - A Plea for Help: Solutions to Serious Problems Currently Experienced by the Federal Judicial System, speech, Saint Louis University Law School, St. Louis, Missouri, 1983 April 7 (Box-folder 210: 4)
  - Panel discussion on oral advocacy, Saint Louis University Law School, St. Louis, Missouri, 1983 April 8 (Box-folder 210: 5)
    Transcript
  - Moot court panel, Stanford Law School, Stanford University, Stanford, California, 1983 May 6 (Box-folder 210: 6)
  - Alumni reunion, Denison University, Granville, Ohio, 1983 June 4 (Box-folder 210: 7)
  - Isaac Parker, Bill Sykes and the Rule of Law, Ben J. Altheimer Lecture, Univeristy of Arkansas, Little Rock, Arkansas, 1983 September 23 (Box-folder 210: 8)
    Typescript, correspondence, and clippings
  - Speech, Conference on Supreme Court Advocacy, Washington, D.C., 1983 October 17 (Box-folder 211: 1)
  - Oral Advocacy: A Disappearing Art, Brainerd Currie Lecture, Mercer University, Macon, Georgia, 1983 October 20 (Box-folder 211: 2)
  - Moot court panel, University of Virginia School of Law, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1983 November 6 (Box-folder 211: 3)
  - Remarks, Oliver Gasch portrait presentation, Washington, D.C., 1983 November 18 (Box-folder 211: 4)
  - Moot court panel, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California, 1984 February 10 (Box-folder 211: 5)
  - Oral Advocacy, speech, Richmond Bar Association, Richmond, Virginia, 1984 February 14 (Box-folder 211: 6)
  - Speech, California Western School of Law, San Diego, California, 1984 March 6 (Box-folder 211: 7)
    Typescript, correspondence, and photographs
  - Speech, College of Law, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Champaign, Illinois, 1984 April 5 (Box-folder 211: 8)
  - Oral Advocacy, speech, Federal Civil Practice Institute, Houston, Texas, 1984 May 2 (Box-folder 211: 9)
  - Circuit Justice assignment, United States District Court, Richmond, Virginia, 1984 June 17-20 (Box-folder 212: 1)
    Correspondence and case materials
  - Panel discussion, Judicial Conference of the Ninth Circuit, Seattle, Washington, 1984 August 15 (Box-folder 212: 2)
  - Convocation address, University of Vermont, Burlington, Vermont, 1984 August 29 (Box-folder 212: 3)
  - Dedicatory address, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, 1984 September 15 (Box-folder 212: 4)
  - Notes on Lawyers, 1984 October 3 (Box-folder 212: 5)
    Typescript
  - Presidential Appointments to the Supreme Court, speech, University of Minnesota Law School, 1984 October 19 (Box-folder 212: 6)
    Typescript, proofs, correspondence, and print
  - Remarks, Award of Merit presentation, Stanford Law School, Stanford University, Stanford, California, 1984 November 3 (Box-folder 212: 7)
  - Remarks, Northern Virginia Young Lawyers Association dinner, Fairfax, Virginia, 1984 December 12 (Box-folder 212: 8)
  - Acceptance speech, Maricopa County Bar Association awards dinner, Tucson, Arizona, 1985 February 8 (Box-folder 212: 9)
    Typescript, correspondence, and clipping
  - Remarks, Virginia Law Review Association banquet, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1985 March 2 (Box-folder 213: 1)
  - Moot court panel, College of Law, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, 1985 April 5 (Box-folder 213: 2)
  - The Lawyer-Statesman in American History, speech, Federalist Society meeting, University of Chicago Law School, Chicago, Illinois, 1985 May 6 (Box-folder 213: 3)
  - Panel discussion, Judicial Conference of the Ninth Circuit, Tucson, Arizona, 1985 May 31 (Box-folder 213: 4)
  - Remarks, Jefferson Society meeting, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1985 September 20 (Box-folder 213: 5)
  - Speech, College of Law, University of Wyoming, Laramie, Wyoming, 1985 October 25 (Box-folder 213: 6)
  - Moot court panel, Harvard Law School, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1985 November 21 (Box-folder 213: 7)
  - The Changing Role of the Supreme Court, Florida State University College of Law, Tallahassee, Florida, 1986 February 6 (Box-folder 213: 8)
  - Constitutional Law and Public Opinion, speech, Suffolk University School of Law, Boston, Massachusetts, 1986 April 10 (Box-folder 214: 1)
  - Commencement address, School of Law, Villanova University, Villanova, Pennsylvania, 1986 May 16 (Box-folder 214: 2)
  - Oral Advocacy, South Texas Law Review, 1986 Summer (Box-folder 214: 3)
  - State and Federal Courts: Points of Friction and Common Concerns, speech, Allegheny County Bar Association Bench-Bar Conference, Champion, Pennsylvania, 1986 June 14 (Box-folder 214: 4)
  - Visiting professorship, Pepperdine University, Malibu, California, 1986 August 2-18 (Box-folder 214: 5)
  - Speech, Judicial Conference of the Ninth Circuit, 1986 August 19-22 (Box-folder 214: 6)
  - The Legal Profession Today, speech, Indiana University School of Law, Bloomington, Indiana, 1986 September 12 (Box-folder 214: 7)
    Typescript, proofs, printed copy, and correspondence
  - President's luncheon, White House, Washington, D.C., 1986 November 25 (Box-folder 214: 8)
  - A Comment on the Instruction of Constitutional Law, Pepperdine Law Review, 1987 (Box-folder 215: 1)
  - In Tribute to Chief Justice Warren E. Burger, Harvard Law Review, 1987 (Box-folder 215: 2)
    Typescript, proofs, and correspondence
  - Federal Judicial Center and Metropolitan Chief Judges meetings, Phoenix, Arizona, 1987 February 3-9 (Box-folder 215: 3)
  - Jurists-in-residence program, University of Hawaii at Manoa, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1987 February 9-13 (Box-folder 215: 4)
    (cancelled residency). Correspondence only
  - The Many Faces of the Bicentennial, speech, American Bar Association meeting, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1987 February 15 (Box-folder 215: 5)
  - Honorary Fellow award, American College of Trial Lawyers meeting, Boca Raton, Florida, 1987 March 9 (Box-folder 215: 6)
  - Remarks, Seminar on the Administration of Justice, Brookings Institution, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1987 April 10-12 (Box-folder 215: 7)
    Typescript, transcript, correspondence, and photographs
  - Speech, American Association of University Women meeting, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1987 May 1 (Box-folder 215: 8)
  - Remarks, National Historic Landmark designation ceremony, Washington, D.C., 1987 May 12 (Box-folder 215: 9)
  - Commencement speech, Boston University, Boston, Massachusetts, 1987 May 17 (Box-folder 216: 1)
    Typescript, correspondence, and print
  - Speech, American Law Institute annual meeting, Washington, D.C., 1987 May 19 (Box-folder 216: 2)
  - Panel discussion, Judicial Conference of the District of Columbia Circuit, Washington, D.C., 1987 May 29 (Box-folder 216: 3)
    List of questions and correspondence
  - The Nature of Judicial Interpretation, speech, Conference on the Judicial Interpretation of the Constitution, American Studies Center, Washington, D.C., 1987 June 12 (Box-folder 216: 4)
  - Speech, Judicial Conference of the Fourth Circuit, Hot Springs, Virginia, 1987 June 26 (Box-folder 216: 5)
  - Visiting lecturer, Tulane Law School program, Rhodes, Greece, 1987 July (Box-folder 216: 6)
  - Federalism in North America, speech, Canadian/American Legal Exchange Program, Montreal, Canada, 1987 September 2 (Box-folder 216: 7)
  - Address, School of Business Administration, University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1987 September 11 (Box-folder 217: 1)
  - Remarks, Citizenship Day ceremony, Washington, D.C., 1987 September 16 (Box-folder 217: 2)
  - Address, Monroe County Bar Association meeting, Rochester, New York, 1987 September 17 (Box-folder 217: 3)
  - Remarks, Fauquier County Commission on the Bicentennial of the United States Constitution ceremony, Warrenton, Virginia, 1987 September 26 (Box-folder 217: 4)
  - The Courts and the Constitution, speech, We the People 200 Bicentennial Celebration, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1987 October 2 (Box-folder 217: 5)
  - Remarks, Canadian/American Legal Exchange Program, Washington, D.C., 1987 October 19 (Box-folder 217: 6)
    Typescript and correspondence, and photographs
  - Speech, Columbia University Law School, New York City, 1987 November 19 (Box-folder 218: 1)
  - Remarks, District of Columbia Bar Association banquet, Washington, D.C., 1987 December 5 (Box-folder 218: 2)
  - Remarks, National Conference of Chief Justices, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1988 January 27 (Box-folder 218: 3)
  - Visiting lecturer, Universidad de Puerto Rico, Rio Piedras, Puerto Rico, 1988 February (Box-folder 218: 4)
  - The Supreme Court: 'The First Hundred Years Were the Hardest', speech, University of Miami School of Law, Coral Gables, Florida, 1988 February 4 (Box-folder 218: 5)
  - Meeting, Board of Directors, Federal Judicial Center, St. Petersburg Beach, Florida, 1988 March 10 (Box-folder 218: 6)
  - Commencement address, Marquette University, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1988 May 22 (Box-folder 219: 1)
    Typescript, printed copy, an correspondence
  - Colloquy, Judicial Conference of the District of Columbia Circuit, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1988 May 23 (Box-folder 219: 2)
  - Panel discussion, Judicial Conference of the Fourth Circuit, White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia, 1988 July 1 (Box-folder 219: 3)
  - Historical Perspectives on the Constitution: Moral and Ethical Views, Feen Endowment Address, Ohavi Zedek Synagogue, Burlington, Vermont, 1988 July 18 (Box-folder 219: 4)
  - Remarks, Conference of Chief Justices, Rockport, Maine, 1988 August 2 (Box-folder 219: 5)
  - Judicial Selection for Constitutional Courts, speech, Bicentennial Australian Legal Convention, Canberra, Australia, 1988 August 29 (Box-folder 220: 1)
  - The Old Order Changeth, speech, Australian Bar Association meeting, Sydney, Australia, 1988 September 3 (Box-folder 220: 2)
  - An Independent Judiciary: Bulwark of the Constitution, speech, College of Law, Northern Illinois University, DeKalb, Illinois, 1988 October 20 (Box-folder 220: 3)
  - Remarks, Ernest F. Hollings Judicial Center dedication ceremony, Charleston, South Carolina, 1988 November 11 (Box-folder 220: 4)
  - Remarks, 125th Anniversary of the Gettysburg Address ceremony, Gettysburg, Pennsylvania, 1988 November 19 (Box-folder 220: 5)
    Typescript, photographs, and correspondence
  - Remarks, United States Marshals Service reception, Washington, D.C., 1988 December 8 (Box-folder 220: 6)
  - Remarks, farewell reception for Charles Fried, Washington, D.C., 1989 January 18 (Box-folder 221: 1)
  - Remarks, Smithsonian Institution Regents' dinner, 1989 January 28 (Box-folder 221: 2)
  - Speech, American Bar Association meeting, Denver, Colorado, 1989 February 6 (Box-folder 221: 3)
  - Speech, College of Law, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, 1989 February 7 (Box-folder 221: 4)
  - Statement of the Chief Justice on Denial of Judicial Pay Increase, 1989 February 7 (Box-folder 221: 5)
  - Board meeting, Federal Judicial Center, Hilton Head, South Carolina, 1989 March 9-11 (Box-folder 221: 6)
  - Press conference, Washington, D.C., 1989 March 15 (Box-folder 221: 7)
  - Remarks, Seminar on the Administration of Justice, Brookings Institute, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1989 April 7 (Box-folder 221: 8)
  - Speech, School of Law, Rutgers University, Newark, New Jersey, 1989 April 11 (Box-folder 222: 1)
  - Testimony, House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service, Washington, D.C., 1989 May 3 (Box-folder 222: 2)
    Typescript of opening statement, transcript of testimony, and correspondence
  - Remarks, commemoration of the fiftieth anniversary of William O. Douglas's appointment to the United States Supreme Court, 1989 May 9 (Box-folder 222: 3)
  - Daniel Webster and the Oratorical Tradition, Daniel Webster Symposium, Dartmouth College, Hanover, New Hampshire, 1989 May 12 (Box-folder 222: 4)
  - Panel discussion, Judicial Conference of the District of Columbia Circuit, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1989 June 6 (Box-folder 223: 1)
  - Invitee, Judicial Conference of the Fourth Circuit, Hot Springs, Virginia, 1989 June 29-July 1 (Box-folder 223: 2)
  - Opening remarks, Cours international de justice constitutionnelle, Aix-en-Provence, France, 1989 July 7-13 (Box-folder 223: 3)
    Printed copy and correspondence
  - Visiting lecturer on American constitutional law, Louisiana State University Summer Study in Law, University of Aix-Marseille III Law School, Aix-en-Provence, France, 1989 July 7-24 (Box-folder 223)
  - Schedule, syllabus, and notes for lectures (Box-folder 223: 4)
  - Travelogue (Box-folder 223: 5)
  - Correspondence and photographs (Box-folder 223: 6-7)
  - American Experience with a Constitutional Court, speech, Swedish Bar Association meeting, Stockholm, Sweden, 1989 August 30 (Box-folder 223: 8)
  - A Tale of Two Bicentennials: America and France, 1789-1989, Frank G. Raichle Lecture, Canisius College, Buffalo, New York, 1989 September 14 (Box-folder 224: 1)
  - Introductory remarks, Plenary Session of the Bicentennial Conference on the Judicial Act of 1789, 1989 September 21 (Box-folder 224: 2)
  - Remarks, Portraits of the American Law exhibition, National Portrait Gallery, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., 1989 October 12 (Box-folder 224: 3)
  - DeRoy Fellow Lecture, University of Michigan Law School, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1989 October 19 (Box-folder 224: 4)
  - Remarks, German-American Conference, American Institute for Contemporary German Studies, Johns Hopkins University, Washington, D.C., 1989 October 25 (Box-folder 224: 5)
  - Remarks, National Center for State Courts luncheon, Washington, D.C., 1989 November 13 (Box-folder 224: 6)
  - Remarks on the death of Arthur J. Goldberg, Washington, D.C., 1990 January 22 (Box-folder 224: 7)
  - Trial Judges I Have Known, Metropolitan Trial Judges Conference, Bethesda, Maryland, 1990 January 26 (Box-folder 225: 1)
  - Remarks, commemorative stamp ceremony, Washington, D.C., 1990 February 2 (Box-folder 225: 2)
  - Board meeting, Federal Judicial Center, Phoenix, Arizona, 1990 February 5 (Box-folder 225: 3)
  - Panel discussion, Canadian Bar Association meeting, Toronto, Canada, 1990 May 4 (Box-folder 225: 4)
  - Remarks, American Law Institute meeting, Washington, D.C., 1990 May 15 (Box-folder 225: 5)
  - Panel discussion, Judicial Conference of the District of Columbia Circuit, Hershey, Pennsylvania, 1990 May 21 (Box-folder 226: 1)
    Transcript, correspondence, and photographs
  - Remarks, Bicentennial Celebration of the United States District Court for the District of Maryland, Baltimore, Maryland, 1990 June 1 (Box-folder 226: 2)
  - Commencement address, Thayer Academy, Braintree, Massachusetts, 1990 June 9 (Box-folder 226: 3)
  - Highlights of the Term, speech, Judicial Conference of the Fourth Circuit, White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia, 1990 June 30 (Box-folder 226: 4)
  - Remarks, International Conference of Chief Justices and the Judicial Conference of the United States, Washington, D.C., 1990 September 10 (Box-folder 226: 5)
  - International Appellate Judges Conference, Washington, D.C., 1990 September 10-14
    - Opening and closing remarks (Box-folder 226: 6)
    - Program and schedules (Box-folder 226: 7)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 226: 8)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 227: 1-7)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 228: 1-2)
  - Remarks on the retirement of Howard T. Markey, 1990 September 18 (Box-folder 228: 3)
  - The Impeachment Clause: A Wild Card in the Constitution, address, Northwestern University School of Law, Evanston, Illinois, 1990 September 27
    - Typescript (Box-folder 228: 4)
    - Proofs and printed copy (Box-folder 228: 5)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 228: 6-7)
  - Public Service and the Legal Profession, speech, Marshall-Wythe School of Law, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1990 October 19 (Box-folder 228: 8)
  - Remarks, Tribute to the Honorable Arthur J. Goldberg, Washington, D.C., 1990 October 15 (Box-folder 228: 9)